Never settle.
The Burial is a drama, history film directed by Margaret Betts.
When a handshake deal goes sour, funeral home owner Jeremiah O'Keefe
enlists charismatic, smooth-talking attorney Willie E.
Gary to save his family business.
Tempers flare and laughter ensues as the unlikely pair bond while
exposing corporate corruption and racial injustice.
Jeremiah O'Keefe, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Willie E. Gary, played by Jamie Foxx.
Mame Downes, played by Jurnee Smollett.
Mike Allred, played by Alan Ruck.
Hal Dockins, played by Mamoudou Athie.
Annette O'Keefe, played by Pamela Reed.
The Burial is a 2023 American legal drama film directed by
Maggie Betts and written by Betts and Doug Wright.
It is loosely based on the true story of lawyer Willie E.
Gary and his client Jeremiah Joseph O'Keefe's lawsuit against the Loewen funeral company, as
documented in the 1999 New Yorker article of the same name by Jonathan Harr.
It stars Jamie Foxx as Gary, Tommy Lee Jones as O'Keefe,
Jurnee Smollett, Mamoudou Athie, and Bill Camp.
It premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 11, 2023, and was released by Amazon MGM
Studios in a limited release on October 6, 2023, prior to streaming via Prime Video on October 13, 2023.
The film explores themes of based on true story, trial, racial
tension, corporate greed, funeral director.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.